Register of the Hungarian subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Hungarian subject collection
1917-2015
XX750
Hoover Institution Archives
16 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 24 digital image files (69.3 MB) (11.1 linear feet)
Pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, serial issues, bulletins, press releases, studies, election campaign literature, and other printed matter relating to various aspects of Hungarian history, including the Revolution of 1918-1919; the Revolution of 1956; Hungarian minorities in other countries; and political, social, and economic conditions and elections in Hungary after 1989. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Access
Collection open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, serial issues, bulletins, press releases, studies, election campaign literature, and other printed matter relating to various aspects of Hungarian history, including the Revolution of 1918-1919; the Revolution of 1956; Hungarian minorities in other countries; and political, social, and economic conditions and elections in Hungary after 1989.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Elections--Hungary.; Hungary--Economic conditions--1989-; Hungary--Emigration and immigration.; Hungary--History--Revolution, 1918-1919.; Hungary--History--Revolution, 1956.; Hungary--Politics and government--1989-; Hungary--Social conditions--1989-.
- Subject File, 1918-1995
  Scope and Contents note
  Flyers, posters, bulletins, brochures, newsletters, reports, pamphlets, newspaper issues, clippings, circulars, leaflets, press releases and miscellanea, arranged chronologically and then alphabetically by subject.
  - Revolution of 1918-1919 - leaflets (Box 1)
  - 1918-1945
    - Census of November 1939 - poster
    - Communist agitation - leaflets, 1920s
    - Red Army officers - biographies and war records, photocopies of flyers, 1944
  - 1945-1989
    - Baranya County (1965) - social and economic conditions for government regional report by Gyula Keresz, 1966
    - Catholic Church - pamphlet by Istvan Barankovics relating to the Catholic Church and faith in Hungary, 1963
    - Ceausescu, Nicolae - analysis of his policies, interview given to Hearst Press, 1978 March
    - Collectivization - poem written by villager from Borjad glorifying social progress, typescript, 1962
    - Communist Party (Magyar Kommunista Part) - facsimile of first posters issued in 1944-1945
    - Elections - flyers, 1947
    - Emigrés - studies issued by various Hungarian anti-communist émigré organizations in the United States, 1958
      Relates to Soviet influence in Hungary, forced labor camps in Hungary, and Hungarian minorities in other communist countries. In Hungarian and English.
    - Housing - pamphlet relating to housing conditions after 1945, Lakas-Viszonyok, 1986
    - Opposition circles - debate on state of affairs in Hungary, report, 1985 June
    - Propaganda in posters
      - Aviation, promotional campaign for, 1950s
        Folder also contains two small election stickers from the late 1940s and a scrap metal collection poster.
      - Museum of Contemporary History
        - Flyer, 1950s
        - Catalog, 1944-1990
  - Revolution of 1956
    - Facsimile
    - Flyers
    - Newspapers
  - 1989-
    - Archives - opening of Soviet archives on Hungarian Communist Party, clippings, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Culture
      - Flyers announcing concerts of classical and rock music celebrating the withdrawal of Soviet troops from Hungary, 1991 June
      - Press releases, newsletters, and flyers issued by the Hungarian Cultural Service, 1991-1992
    - Defense, national - Ministry of Defense bulletin on official government position, 1993
    - Economic reforms and privatization - government publications, brochures, magazines, academic analysis, 1990-1993
    - Education - higher education system reform, brochures and bulletins, 1993
    - Elections (Box 3)
      Party programs, newsletters, newspaper issues, and leaflets issued by various parties for the national elections. In Hungarian and some in English.
      - General, electoral laws of 1989 and 1990
      - 1990
      - 1994
    - Environment - flyers against water-power station on Slovak-Hungarian border, Gabcikovo-Nagymaros, and polluting of Danube river, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Hungarian News Agency - weekly bulletin
      - 1992
      - 1993
      - 1994 (Box 5)
    - McDonald - Budapest
    - May Day - newsletters, newspaper issues, brochures, and flyers relating to the celebration of May 1, 1991-1993
    - Media war - government statements and political analysis of free media, 1992
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs - official press releases of Hungarian government on current issues, 1992-1994
      - General
        - General
        - Press file, maps and brochures on Hungary
      - European Union
      - NATO membership
      - Regional cooperation
    - Minorities - flyers, posters, official government press releases (Box 6)
      - General, press releases of Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1992-1993
        Includes material on war in former Yugoslavia.
      - Hungarian minority
        - Czechoslovakia
        - Romania
        - Yugoslavia
      - Ukrainians in Hungary
    - Political parties, 1989-1992
      Programs, bulletins, brochures, newsletters, reports, pamphlets, newspaper issues, clippings, circulars, leaflets, and miscellanea. In Hungarian and English.
      - General (Box 7)
        - General
        - Agrarian and peasant parties
        - Smallholders party
      - Fiatal Demokratak Szovetsege, FIDESZ (Union of Young Democrats) (Box 8)
      - Keresztenydemokrata Neppart, KDNP (Christian Democratic People's Party)
      - Magyar Demokrata Fsrum, MDF (Hungarian Democratic Forum)
      - Magyar Igazsag Es Elet Partja (Box 9)
      - Magyar Munkaspart
      - Magyar Neppart
      - Magyar Nemzeti Part
      - Magyar Oktober Part
      - Magyar Radicalis Part
      - Magyar Szocialista Part (Socialist Party)
      - Magyaroszagi Szocialdemokrata Part
      - Nemzeti Demokrata Szovetseg
      - Szabad Demokratak, SZDSZ (Alliance of Free Democrats) (Box 10)
    - Press - newspaper issues and magazines reflecting process of political evolution since 1989 (Box 11)
    - Public opinion - booklet, issued by the Hungarian Public Opinion Research Center, and clippings, 1987, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Soros, George - correspondence on Hungarian internal politics
    - Trade unions - brochures and bulletins, 1990-1995
- Memorabilia, 1956-1994 (Box 13)
  Tote bags, buttons from 1994 national elections, pre-1945 national flag damaged in the 1956 Revolution, and flags with images of Karl Marx and Vladimir I. Lenin.
- Incremental Materials, 2015, undated
  - 24 digital image files documenting a political protest in Budapest and a political sticker relating to the Syrian refugee crisis, 2015 October (Reading room Workstation)
  - Material not yet described (Boxes 14-19)